<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>E Alan Hill - Articles</title>
    <description>I love Android and the work I do. I work closely with my clients to deliver the best possible solution for their needs.</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning Android</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I went to an event hosted by a local App Development Agency. It was a great time and, while there, I ran into a college student who brought his college’s computer club. He asked me if I had any thoughts on how to teach his fellow students programming. It was a great question to ask an experienced engineer, and I figured I would share some of the advice I gave him here, but specifically about Android.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 03:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /learning-android</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning-android</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Is A ScrumMaster Necessary</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I have worked within the Agile framework since my first internship. I really like it’s fluidity, ability to adapt to changing requirements, and flexible structure. Recently, I started working with a client who has strictly implemented the Agile method, including a position I had not encountered previously. I had heard about it, but no company I have worked with has actually given someone this position as their sole role.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 15:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /is-a-scrum-master-necessary</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/is-a-scrum-master-necessary</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Instant Apps The Future</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As everyone should know in the Android developer community, Google released the Instant App SDK for companies to start adding them to their apps. For those who are not in the loop, Instant Apps are small versions of your app users download from a link on the internet. They last just as long as they need to on the users phone. But, I’m not going to rehash Instant Apps here, there are plenty of other articles out there &lt;a href=&quot;https://willowtreeapps.com/ideas/an-introduction-to-android-instant-apps&quot;&gt;explaining what they are&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, I’m asking the question: Are Instant Apps the future of mobile apps?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 15:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /are-instant-apps-the-future</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/are-instant-apps-the-future</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
