<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>biomadeira.github.io/jasper/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>I love Android and the work I do. I work closely with my clients to deliver the best possible solution for their needs.</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> E Alan Hill</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Is A ScrumMaster Necessary</title>
	  <link>//is-a-scrum-master-necessary</link>
	  <author>E Alan Hill</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-07-31T16:55:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//is-a-scrum-master-necessary</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I have worked within the Agile framework since my first internship. I really like it’s fluidity, ability to adapt to changing requirements, and flexible structure. Recently, I started working with a client who has strictly implemented the Agile method, including a position I had not encountered previously. I had heard about it, but no company I have worked with has actually given someone this position as their sole role.</p>

<p>What is this position? Well, the person is a ScrumMaster.</p>

<p>As I’ve been working with this client, I noticed something very odd: the ScrumMaster hasn’t added any value to the team. Instead, he seems to enforce a process, which is something Agile is meant to avoid. This, in turn, seems to have dramatically hindered the team from delivering a product.</p>

<p>This situation has made me ask: Does Agile Scrum require a ScrumMaster?</p>

<h5>What is Scrum?</h5>

<p>First, Agile Scrum is a specific Agile framework for completing complex projects, according to the Scrum Alliance. Very vague…</p>

<p>The Scrum Alliance does provide a little more description of what Scrum includes. There must be a Product Owner, who creates a wish list of product requirements, which become the backlog. The team then works on a small portion of the backlog in Sprints, which last 2-4 weeks. Scrum includes daily stand ups to assess progress and roadblocks. Finally, at the end of a sprint, Scrum aims to have a shippable product for the Product Owner to review. This all sounds like normal Agile processes.</p>

<h5>What is a ScrumMaster?</h5>

<p>Within Scrum, what is a ScrumMaster? Well, they are the facilitator for the Agile Team, responsible for ensuring the Scrum process is understood and enacted. They ensure external interactions are only beneficial to the team. Scrum.org has a long list of other responsibilities:</p>

<ul>
  <li>lead by example</li>
  <li>safe environment</li>
  <li>facilitate consensus</li>
  <li>read the room</li>
  <li>be patient</li>
  <li>don’t solve</li>
  <li>be comfortable with failure</li>
  <li>care for people</li>
  <li>low tolerance for impediments</li>
</ul>

<p>That’s a lot of things for one person, which cannot be easily measured in an individual.</p>

<p>But, looking over this list, they look a lot like another list of responsibilities for a different position: Project Manager.</p>

<h5>What are Project Managers?</h5>

<p>Doing a quick Google search, a  Project Manager is the person in charge of a project. It is their job to plan the project and determine it’s budget. Overall, their job is to the lead the project to the desired conclusion.</p>

<p>So, if a Project Managers main role is to be the project leader, then they too must</p>

<ul>
  <li>lead by example</li>
  <li>provide a safe environment</li>
  <li>read the room</li>
  <li>be patient</li>
  <li>don’t solve</li>
  <li>be comfortable with failure</li>
  <li>care for people</li>
  <li>low tolerance for impediments</li>
</ul>

<p>The only responsibility a ScrumMaster is supposed to do that is not on the above list is “facilitate consensus”. But is this really necessary? Wouldn’t leading by example cover this? Don’t Project Managers want people to work together? Wouldn’t that require a consensus?</p>

<p>Basically, I’m saying a Project Manager does everything a ScrumMaster does, with one added benefit, they have a stake in the results of the project. They are the person ultimately responsible for the success or failure of the project.</p>

<h5>Is a ScrumMaster Needed?</h5>

<p>No, I don’t believe a ScrumMaster is needed on every team.</p>

<p>What do I mean? Well, if a team is just starting to transition to an Agile process, then they might require a dedicated ScrumMaster. This way, there is someone on the team who can guide them through the change, to simplify the transition and help with any questions the team might have.</p>

<p>However, if the team is well established, or there are people who have experience with Agile, then there is no reason to have a full time ScrumMaster on the team. They become a drain of team, and therefore company, resources.</p>

<p>I’ve noticed the majority of software companies use the Agile process these days. Which means, a majority of software engineers are already familiar with Agile. So, let’s get rid of this old role and replace it with someone who is a true leader: the Project Manager.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
